Guide to the Balmori Associates Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Writings by Diana Balmori, 1970-2006; Series II
  - Articles
    - "Cranbrook: The Invisible Landscape," JSAH 53:30-60, 30-60, 1994 March (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - "Reframing the Work of City-Making," Korean Landscape Architecture, 162-171, 1995 September (Box 13, Folder 14)
      In Korean & English.
    - "NTT," Landscape Design, No.2, 1995 (Box 13, Folder 15)
      In Japanese & English.
    - "Landscape at Yale," Landscape Design, No.5, 159-163, 1996 (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - "Naturaleza y Artificio," Summa, No. 3D, 61-65, 1998 April-May (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - "Breathing Space," Architecture, Vol. 7, 108-109, 2004 (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Book chapter or entry
    - "Beatrix Farrand, 1872-1959," in Long Island Country Houses and Their Architects, 1860-1940 (ed. Robert MacKay, Anthony Baker & Carol Traynor), Society for the Preservation of Long Island Antiquities in assoc. with Norton & Co., 163-165, 1997 (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - Chapter I.8, "A productive stormwater park (Framington, Minnesota)," in Handbook of Water Sensitive Planning and Design (ed. Robert L. France) CRC Press, LLC, 175-192, 2002 (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - Book Review: Review of "Order, Family and Continuity in Buenos Aires" by Mark Szuchman, American Historical Review, Vol. 95 Issue 2, 633-634, 1990 April (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - Essay: "City/Memorial", 2002 (Box 13, Folder 23)
    On PBS website: http://www.pbs.org/americarebuilds/ imagining/index.html.
  - Conference paper: with Michael T. Huguenin, Robert E. Unsworth, and Anton P. Giedt, "Enhancing Damaged Public Assets: Perspectives from Landscape Architects and Planners," 14 pages, 1997 (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - Review
    - "Irish Hunger Memorial," e-OCULUS: The American Institute of Architects New York Chapter Newsletter, 2002 August 15 (Box 13, Folder 24)
    - "Around Downtown: The Viewing Wall," e-OCULUS: The American Institute of Architects New York Chapter Newsletter, 2002 September 4 (Box 13, Folder 25)
  - Statement: Faculty Show, Yale School of Architecture Faculty Show, 1987 (Box 13, Folder 26)
  - Unpublished
    - "Japan and Landscape Design: The Meiji Shrine Iris Garden", 1993 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - '"The Evolution of the Concept Park: The Productive Park", 1994 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - '"Imagining the New Urban Park: A Blueprint for the Next Century", 1995 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - "Lit Up", Undated (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - "The Next Urban Space: Letting the Earth Come Through", Undated (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Course description & evaluation: F&ES/Arch 741 b Collaboration in Landscape (With William R. Burch, Jr.), Yale F&ES/Arch bulletin, New Haven, CT, 1989 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Lectures
    - "About Landscape: A Theoretical Stance", 1990 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - "Presentation on Light," Yale School of Forestry and Environmental Studies, New Haven, CT, 1993 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - "Intellectual Path," University of Pennsylvania, Philadelphia, PA, 1993 September (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - "Infrastructure and the City," The Future of the American City Symposium, The Alliance for Architecture, New Haven, Connecticut, 1994 February 26 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - "Aesthetics and Ecology: Some Attempts at Connection," The Museum of Contemporary Art (MOCA), Los Angeles, California, 1994 May 6 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - I. "What Generates Form?" and II. "The Reinventing of Nature," University of Minnesota, College of Architecture and Landscape Architecture, Minneapolis, Minnesota, 1994 May 23 (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - "Paris Lecture," Parks and Their Cities: The Urban Landscape, A Conference at The American Center, Paris, France, 1994 September 30 (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - "Three Essays on Landscape Form," Harvard University, Graduate School of Design, Cambridge, Massachusetts, 1994 December 7 (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - "Transitory Gardens" (with Margaret Morton), Municipal Art Society of New York, New York, New York, 1994 (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - "Reinterpreting Park Design for the Changing American City: The Farmington Canal and Beyond," New Haven Colony Historical Society, New Haven, Connecticut, 1995 0ct 24 (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - "Linear Parks: American Promenade," Rice Design Alliance, Rice University, Houston, Texas, 1995 November 1 (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - "On Form-Giving: Describing the Process," Harvard University, Graduate School of Design, Cambridge, Massachusetts, 1995 November 11 (Box 14, Folder 18)
    - "Saying Good-bye to the American Lawn," Easton Library, Easton, Connecticut, 1996 April 16 (Box 14, Folder 19)
    - "Storm King: Lecture on Sculpture and Landscape", 2000 (Box 14, Folder 21)
    - "About Light," Eye of the Beholder Lecture Series, Isabella Stewart Gardner Museum, Boston, Massachusetts, 1996 April 25 (Box 14, Folder 20)
    - "Temporary Memorials," Van Alen Institute, New York, New York, 2002 March 11 (Box 14, Folder 22)
    - "Memorial: The Furnishings of Grief", 2002 (Box 14, Folder 23)
    - "The Future of Urban Space," introduction for Lecture Series, Yale School of Architecture, New Haven, Connecticut, 2003 (Box 14, Folder 24)
    - "Building Types and City Changes: Disappearing Typologies," Newman Institute, Baruch College, New York, New York, 2003 (Box 14, Folder 25)
    - "Landscape and the Beautiful," Center for Architecture, New York, New York, 2003 (Box 14, Folder 26)
    - "Thoughts on the Present Junction of Aesthetics and Ecology", Undated (Box 14, Folder 27)
      - Cold Spring Conference
        - Transcript of session I, Cold Spring, New York with edited version, 1985 November 2-3, 1989 November (Box 14, Folder 29)
          General note
          Part I is the full transcript. Part 2 is an edited draft by Gerald Allen
        - Transcripts of session II, Dumbarton Oaks, Washington, D.C.and session III, River Farm, 1989 May 26, 1990 February 26 (Box 14, Folder 30)
          Combined in same volume with CSC III
    - "Courtyards," Yale University, New Haven, Connecticut, Undated (Box 14, Folder 28)
- Computer file (Box 39, Reel 37–38)
  Original born digital files, as well as preservation masters, may not be accessed due to their fragility. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist request that they be made. Born digital files cannot be accessed remotely. System requirements include a Manuscripts and Archives computer and file viewing software.